Joshua Garst, Software Engineer

joshuagarst@gmail.com | (940)783-0938 | Bentonville, Arkansas

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/joshua-garst | Portfolio: joshua-garst-portfolio-website.netlify.app | GitHub: github.com/testler

Summary

A highly experienced software engineer with a strong background in fulfillment logistics, management, and e-commerce. Possessing education in front-end development, I am able to bring a philosophy of excellence to my work and create effective teams to solve complex problems. My diverse background and knowledge in both technical and non-technical areas allows me to approach challenges from multiple angles and find the best solution.

Skills

Programing languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Python, SQL, TypeScript, and NoSQL

Technical tool: React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, Angular, Webpack and PostgreSQL

Software Engineering Projects

All Things By AV:

- Developed e-commerce storefront using Angular and Java Spring Boot
- Implemented endpoints protection and employed PostgreSQL for data storage
- Utilized Angular for reactive UI/UX and managed entire development process as sole developer

Movie App:

- Developed a web application using React.js and Node.js to provide an intuitive movie discovery experience
- Utilized Agile methodologies and Git/GitHub for efficient code management and version control
- Collaborated with a team of 3 developers to deliver a successful final product with positive feedback from users

Cyber Defense Platform:

- Developed interactive educational game using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Utilized Agile development methodologies and version control with Git and GitHub
- Focused on JavaScript development and optimizing performance for different devices and browsers

Date Night Organizer:

- Developed a service-oriented web application using Git/GitHub for version control
- Utilized MongoDB, Mongoose, and EJS for database management and data modeling
- Aimed to provide a personalized experience for users by providing them with tailored date night ideas

Education

General Assembly, Software Engineering, September 2022:

Coursework in: Web3, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Git, Github, API implementation, REST web services, SQL, NoSQL, Python, Node.js, React.js, MongoDB, express.js, Django, mongoose, software design

Work Experience

Full-Stack Software Engineer, Freelance, (august 2022 - Present):

- Created and maintained NoSQL and SQL databases using MongoDB and PostgreSQL
- Developed Fullstack application using typescript, angular, react, and java backend
- Required the ability to handle multiple projects at once
- Team members had to be confident and pay attention to detail to meet the client's high standards

Delivery Driver, Lowes Home Improvement Store, (March 2018 - February 2021):

- Managed and planned delivery routes, ensuring timely and efficient delivery of merchandise
- Led team of delivery personnel in loading, unloading, and installation of appliances and store equipment

Lead Setter, Sunpro Solar (April 2021 - September 2021):

- Developed and presented persuasive communication to potential clients, resulting in scheduled appointments
- Proven ability to meet or exceed sales targets and production standards